August 1, 1966, was the day our innocence was shattered.
Tower is a animation, crime, documentary film directed by Keith Maitland.
Combining archival footage with rotoscopic animation, Tower reveals the action-packed untold stories of the witnesses, heroes and
survivors of America’s first mass school shooting, when the worst in one man brought out the best in so many others.
Claire Wilson James, played by Violett Beane.
Allen Crum, played by Chris Doubek.
Houston McCoy, played by Blair Jackson.
Ramiro "Ray" Martinez, played by Louie Arnette.
Rita Starpattern, played by Josephine McAdam.
Aleck Hernandez Jr., played by Aldo Ordoñez.
Tower is a 2016 American mostly-animated documentary film about the 1966 shootings at the
University of Texas at Austin directed and produced by Keith Maitland.
The film follows the shooting from the perspectives of several survivors, recreating
their recounts via actors filmed and later animated in rotoscoping.
The film premiered on March 13, 2016, at South by Southwest, before receiving a
limited release by Kino Lorber in the United States on September 28, 2016.
It was later aired on television on the PBS series Independent Lens.
The film explores themes of violence in schools,
massacre, adult animation, school shooting.